https://www.phoenixherp.com/about/how-we-help/success-stories.html

Phoenix Herpetological Society : About : Conservation Efforts : Success Stories
Virtual
K-12 Ed.
Desert Wildlife And Safety
Need Help?
Adoptions
Surrender A Pet
Surrender Form
Rattlesnake Rescue & Removal
Have You Seen Something Suspicious?
Virtually Adopt An Animal
Contribute to Become A Conservation Patron!
Gift Certificates
Redbubble!
Etsy Shop!
Virtual
K-12 Ed.
Desert Wildlife And Safety
Need Help?
Adoptions
Surrender A Pet
Surrender Form
Rattlesnake Rescue & Removal
Have You Seen Something Suspicious?
Virtually Adopt An Animal
Contribute to Become A Conservation Patron!
Gift Certificates
Redbubble!
Etsy Shop!
2019 End of Year letter
This is Lindsey, I adopted a bearded dragon with MBD from you a month or so ago. I wanted you and your fellow staff members to know how well he is doing and how much my students love him. His name is now Ivar which who was a Viking king who was disabled. Ivar surprisingly loves all the kids and certainly has his favorites. He has shown no aggression or fear when it comes to our classroom. He attends many classes to teach kids about reptiles as well as the large amount or work it takes to care for them. I have had several parents tell me how much of an impact him being in my classroom has had for their students. Many students struggling to engage with school have become very attached to him and he has become a motivator to those students. He also is a mascot for students with disabilities and I talk to students about how he perseveres even though he has a handicap. We all really appreciate you allowing us to adopt him and allowing my students the opportunity to have an animal around with disabilities same as theirs. He is extremely beloved to us and we are so thankful for his presence in our classroom.
A “TAIL” OF A TALE
Most people do not think of an alligator as a lovable companion (for obvious reasons).  Alligators are natural predators with fearsome features such as protective osteoderms, muscular tails, and bone shattering chomps.  Also, they are illegal in most of the country without government-issued permits.
Mr. Stubbs, a 12 year old American Alligator (Alligator mississippiensis), was illegally held with 31 others by one man in California.  Based on X-ray observations, trauma had been induced to his remaining vertebrae, most likely from a larger alligator in the group.  During feeding frenzies, alligators will eat everything and anything fleshy, including their own kind.
Stubbs has spent most of his life tailless, which is a serious handicap for an alligator.  Crocodilian tails are the primary method of locomotion in the water. It also stabilizes their bodies on land, and stores vital nutrients during wintertime, similar to a bear surviving hibernation.
When Mr. Stubbs arrived at PHS, he was thin, panicked at feeding time, and generally high stressed and under nourished: not a good combination for an animal trying to survive under any settings.   When the curators at PHS first saw Mr. Stubbs, an overwhelming sense of need to help this clearly special needs creature came over the group.  Stubbs had a second chance at life.  After more than 6 months of specialized feeding and attention, Stubbs looked and acted more like the other alligators and less like the picked-on animal he once was.
Mr. Stubbs lived at PHS for years before his guardian angel, Dr. Marc Jacofsky, visited the facility and met the animal that would change his life.  In January 2010, he started a research project with the mission of creating a new tail for Mr. Stubbs. Dr. Jacofsky and a team of scientists, doctors, and researchers worked tirelessly to engineer a prosthetic tail for Mr. Stubbs.  While human prosthetics have been around for thousands of years, in 2012 the very first alligator prosthetic was developed by the CORE Institute in Phoenix, AZ in conjunction with Dr. Justin Georgi Midwestern University for Mr. Stubbs.  It had to be just right, with proper proportions, weight distribution, density, and size for the growing alligator to maintain normal posture and movement while walking as well as balance and locomotion in the water.
Mr. Stubbs never fought his new tail or hesitated once it was harnessed on his back legs.  He immediately slid into the swimming pool where he gets his physical therapy and began swimming as any normal alligator would.  It’s an amazing transformation that has drastically improved his quality of life.  He is now able to swim efficiently, walk straight when he is on land, and enjoy moving like an alligator should.  If PHS had not rescued him, Mr. Stubbs would likely have drowned or starved to death.
Mr. Stubbs lives at the PHS facility in Scottsdale, AZ and will stay there for the rest of his life. Alligators, especially special needs alligators like Mr. Stubbs, need specific care that individuals or families are not allowed to provide.  His new family members are his alligator roommate, Baby, and his caretakers at PHS.  They help him thrive with physical therapy, exercise, and a healthy living environment.
Dr. Marc remains “attached at the hip”-bone to Mr. Stubbs.  He continues to improve and develop his prosthetics as well as visit him on a regular basis. Since individuals cannot own alligators in Arizona without a permit, Dr. Marc has essentially adopted Mr. Stubbs through sponsorship.  Dr. Marc has been and continues to be the reason that Mr. Stubbs has improved so drastically and maintains a better quality of life before his rescue.
New process on how the tail is made can be found on Artec3D's website
A DRAGON’S TALE
Prometheus is a Chinese Water Dragon (Physignathus cocincinus) whose story can make even the worst reptile-phobic person appreciate his life and will to live.
He was surrendered to the Phoenix Herpetological Society by an owner who said they could no longer care for him.  At first glance, he was listless, did not move or open his eyes and clearly needed special attention.
After two weeks of being force fed and not showing improvement, Prometheus was taken to a local exotic vet.  After the vet evaluated his condition, he explained that Prometheus had had a rough life, with many years of neglect and that he was older than the owner had stated at the time of surrender. His body size was less than half the size of a healthy adult Chinese Water Dragon and he must have had poor quality nutrition for his entire life.  The vet also found a history of fractures all over his body, including a recently healed jaw fracture.  In addition, Prometheus had an eye infection that had been untreated for months because prior to surrender, he had not received proper medical treatment either. The vet prescribed antibiotics for the eye infection and a calcium supplement to mitigate the devastating condition of his bones.
Vicky Kramer, a volunteer at PHS, has always admired Chinese Water Dragons, and offered to foster Prometheus for his recovery.  She constantly monitored, cared for, and prayed for Prometheus.  She provided proper habitat and husbandry for him including increasing his habitat’s humidity, providing proper heat and lighting, manually feeding Prometheus daily, and administering his medications.  Vicky devoted herself to the rehabilitation and survival of her new foster animal and after a month and a half of tireless dedication, she began to see improvement in Prometheus.  First, she saw color changes in his face (mouth and skin) and then his eyes.  His energy level increased; he was on the mend!  He was still unable to feed himself, so she continued her mission of healing this animal.  After two and a half months of daily care and countless hours of effort and concern for Prometheus, he finally began to eat on his own.  For a foster parent like Vicky, this is a huge victory!
Ever since then, Prometheus has grown and thrived.  Vicky was so impressed by his will to live and perseverance that she adopted him from PHS and added him to her family permanently.  She says that now he is very energetic and is always watching what his human companions are doing.  He likes to be held in a towel and petted on the head.  She says he is sweet, an “amazing eater”, and that he jumps across his habitat, in and out of the pool, and seems very happy.
We are sure that Prometheus is grateful for his new lease on life and his new, loving family.  You can see that he is now happy and healthy and getting ready for his first Halloween with his new sister!
Fundraiser sponsor
Fundraiser sponsor
Mailing Address Only!
20701 N. Scottsdale Rd, Suite 107 - 401
Scottsdale, AZ 85255
Phone
(602) 550 - 1090 Snake Hotline or Animal ID (8 am - 9 pm)
(480) 513-4377 x 2 For Surrenders, Adoptions, Lost & Founds
x 3 for Camps, Corporate, Media, Specialized Education
x 5 for Tours, Field Trips, Education Programs
x 6 for Volunteers (Youth & Adult), Internships, & Community Service
Email Us Your General Question!
Monday - Saturday 8:00 am - 5:00 pm
All Visits By Appointments Only
Closed Major Holidays
Tax ID- 501(c)(3) 02-0678512
Who We Are
What We Do
How to Help
Event Calendar
Email Sign Up
© 2020 Phoenix Herpetological Society
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
What Information Do We Collect?
When you visit our website you may provide us with two types of information: personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis and website use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our website.
Personal Information You Choose to Provide
We may request that you voluntarily supply us with personal information, including your email address, postal address, home or work telephone number and other personal information for such purposes as correspondence, placing an order, requesting an estimate, or participating in online surveys.
If you choose to correspond with us through email, we may retain the content of your email messages together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone.
Website Use Information
Similar to other websites, our site may utilize a standard technology called "cookies" (see explanation below, "What Are Cookies?") and web server logs to collect information about how our website is used. Information gathered through cookies and server logs may include the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our website, and the sites visited just before and just after ours. This information is collected on an aggregate basis. None of this information is associated with you as an individual.
How Do We Use the Information That You Provide to Us?
Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing service and support and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our website, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. The lists used to send you product and service offers are developed and managed under our traditional standards designed to safeguard the security and privacy of all personal information provided by our users. You may at any time to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers.
What Are Cookies?
Cookies are a feature of web browser software that allows web servers to recognize the computer used to access a website. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's web browser on the user's hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that website by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user's transactions on related web pages. This makes it easier for a user to move from web page to web page and to complete commercial transactions over the Internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalized.
How Do We Use Information Collected From Cookies?
We use website browser software tools such as cookies and web server logs to gather information about our website users' browsing activities, in order to constantly improve our website and better serve our users. This information assists us to design and arrange our web pages in the most user-friendly manner and to continually improve our website to better meet the needs of our users and prospective users.
Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by users to our website as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our website and evaluate our website's visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual email address or any personally identifying information about you.
Notice of New Services and Changes
Occasionally, we may use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our website, new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. As a user of our website, you will be given the opportunity to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers by clicking on a response box when you receive such an offer or by sending us an email request.
How Do We Secure Information Transmissions?
When you send confidential personal information to us on our website, a secure server software which we have licensed encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. The information is scrambled en route and decoded once it reaches our website.
Other email that you may send to us may not be secure unless we advise you that security measures will be in place prior to your transmitting the information. For that reason, we ask that you do not send confidential information such as Social Security, credit card, or account numbers to us through an unsecured email.
How Do We Protect Your Information?
Information Security -- We utilize encryption/security software to safeguard the confidentiality of personal information we collect from unauthorized access or disclosure and accidental loss, alteration or destruction.
Evaluation of Information Protection Practices -- Periodically, our operations and business practices are reviewed for compliance with organization policies and procedures governing the security, confidentiality and quality of our information.
Employee Access, Training and Expectations -- Our organization values, ethical standards, policies and practices are committed to the protection of user information. In general, our business practices limit employee access to confidential information, and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons, processes and transactions.
How Can You Access and Correct Your Information?
You may request access to all your personally identifiable information that we collect online and maintain in our database by emailing us using the contact form provided to you within the site structure of our website.
Do We Disclose Information to Outside Parties?
We may provide aggregate information about our customers, sales, website traffic patterns and related website information to our affiliates or reputable third parties, but this information will not include personally identifying data, except as otherwise provided in this privacy policy.
What About Legally Compelled Disclosure of Information?
We may disclose information when legally compelled to do so, in other words, when we, in good faith, believe that the law requires it or for the protection of our legal rights.
Permission to Use of Materials
The right to download and store or output the materials in our website is granted for the user's personal use only, and materials may not be reproduced in any edited form. Any other reproduction, transmission, performance, display or editing of these materials by any means mechanical or electronic without our express written permission is strictly prohibited. Users wishing to obtain permission to reprint or reproduce any materials appearing on this site may contact us directly.
Terms & Conditions
Terms & Conditions
Donation Refund Policy
We are grateful for your donation and support of our organization. If you have made an error in making your donation or change your mind about contributing to our organization please contact us.
Refunds are returned using the original method of payment. If you made your donation by credit card, your refund will be credited to that same credit card.
Automated Recurring Donation Cancellation
Ongoing support is important to enabling projects to continue their work, so we encourage donors to continue to contribute to projects over time. But if you must cancel your recurring donation, please notify us.
